macewan.ca 2017-12-25

# Popup Form

## Privacy

MacEwan University is committed to protecting the privacy and confidentiality of personal information. All personal information that is collected by MacEwan University, whether through this website (www.MacEwan.ca) or by other means, is collected and managed on the authority of the Alberta Freedom of Information and Protection of Privacy Act, the university’s Information Security and Records and Information Management Policies, and other policies that may be specific to the function.

## Automatically Collected Information

MacEwan University web servers automatically collect and store the following information from its websites:

  * The Internet Protocol (IP) Address and domain name used for the computer accessing the website.
  * The type of browser and operating system;
  * The date and time of the visit;
  * The web pages or services accessed; and
  * Popular search phrases.

Information collected automatically is maintained in a secure environment. As per the Information Security Policy, the university will not use individually identifiable data for other purposes, unless required to do so as part of an internal investigation or other law enforcement purpose. 

Summary use reports will be created and used to improve usability on our sites and to help support the online needs of visitors by assessing system performance, and improving web services and website management. 

##  Personal Information Provided Voluntarily in Email and Web Forms 

Some personal information, including but not limited to name and email address, may be provided voluntarily by users of MacEwan University websites to request services. Personal information provided voluntarily by email or by filling out a web form will be used only for the purpose for which it was provided and uses directly consistent with that purpose, in conformance with applicable policies and legislation governing the handling of personal information. Storage of Information Outside of Canada In order to improve website performance and user experience, some MacEwan University websites use Google’s web analytics service that stores information outside of Canada where it may not receive the same privacy protection it receives in Canada. 

##  Links to Third Party Sites 

MacEwan University websites contain some links to other sites. While MacEwan endeavours to link to other sites that have similar high standards and respect for privacy, we are not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of other sites. 

##  More Information 

Questions or concerns regarding management of MacEwan websites and the information collection and use practices connected with them should be directed to: MacEwan University, Information Technology Services, Manager of Web Services, 780-497-5702. 

Questions or concerns regarding privacy protection may be directed to: Information Management and Privacy Office; phone: 780-497-5423; Email: [Privacy@MacEwan.ca](mailto:Privacy@MacEwan.ca?subject=Privacy%20Inquiry); website: [www.MacEwan.ca/FOIP](http://www.macewan.ca/foip). 

The personal information on this form is collected under s.33(c) of the Freedom of Information and Protection of Privacy Act and will be protected under Part 2 of that Act for the purpose of facilitating your communication with MacEwan University. Questions concerning this collection should be directed to Privacy and Information Management at MacEwan University at 10700 – 104 Avenue, Edmonton, AB. T5J 4S2 or by email at privacy@macewan.ca.
